### **Tyler Friedman**

(248) 310-2539 | Chicago, IL | tyler@idealogs.org | tylerfriedman.org

#### **OBJECTIVE**

A talented, self-motivated IT professional with entrepreneurial spirit seeks the position of Entry Level Web Developer in a thriving company. Comes with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Mathematics and two years independent experience of full-stack Django web development.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel

Completed 4 credits towards a Master of Science in Electrical Engineering Graduate Student Scholarship (100% tuition waiver and living stipend) Dropped out to found the Idealogical Foundation, Inc.

## University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Bachelor of Science with Distinction, Computer Science and Mathematical Sciences

#### **SKILLS**

Web Frameworks: Django

Languages: Python, C, C++, C#, MATLAB, Erlang, HTML, CSS, jQuery, LaTeX

Applications: Git, PDB, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, memcached, Celery, RabbitMQ, nginx, gunicorn, borg

### RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Programming & Data Structures, Computer Game Design, Databases, Algorithms, Coding Theory, Operating Systems, Computer Security, Distributed Functional Programming, Intro to Combinatorics, Probability Theory

# RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Idealogical Foundation, Inc., Flagstaff, AZ

Founder, Lead Developer

Sep 2017 – Present

Oct 2016 - Mar 2017

Sep 2010 – Apr 2015

GPA: 3.72/4.00

GPA: 94.5/100

- Built a crowdsourcing website for understanding controversial topics (idealogs.org) in Django
- Mastered fundamentals of full-stack web development including: M-V-T architecture, ORMs, rapid prototyping, responsive design, search, caching, asynchronous task management, VPS hosting, deduplicating backups, and profiling
- Developed idea from infancy to production without prior web development experience or outside help
- Invented a new model for aggregating and refining contextual information
- Managed all aspects of the project including: engineering, financing, corporation formation, and trademark application

## Coconino Community College, Flagstaff, AZ

Adjunct Lecturer, Mathematics

Jan 2018 – Aug 2019

- Taught algebra to students that struggle considerably with the subject
- Devised lectures with focus on emotional aspects of learning to make courses approachable
- Brought positive energy and humor to lectures to keep students engaged
- Emphasized strong studying habits and pushed students to make connections between time investment and achievement

## Transcaucasian Trail Association, Svaneti, Republic of Georgia

Project Manager

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

- Provided logistical support to project attempting to connect Black and Caspian Seas via one long-distance hiking trail through the Caucasus Mountains (transcaucasiantrail.org)
- Stewarded the project home base and operations center to keep project running efficiently
- Organized food and gear shopping, and managed crews when they were not in the field

Crew Leader Jun 2017 – Sep 2017

- Designed and constructed reroutes of deteriorating hiking trails
- Supervised crews of 8-12 international volunteers on 8-day projects in a backcountry environment
- Managed diverse personalities from varied ages and backgrounds into cohesive working units
- Constantly monitored health, energy, and morale of group to ensure a safe and productive working environment